-  你算出来我们在哪里了吗  - 仪器还在受涡流影响
- You've calculated where we are? - The instruments are still affected.
但是我觉得这是1984年的伦敦
But I think it's 1984. London.
- 找到它了 - 博士 你去哪里
- Found it! - Doctor, where are you going?
时间走廊  我想找出是什么东西弄出来的
The Time Corridor. I want to find out what all this is about.
这么大的疏忽
Such neglect.
百年前这个地方应该熙熙攘攘 热闹非凡
A hundred years ago, this place would've been bustling.
如果我们能找出是谁在操纵时光走廊 就有可能
It might be again, if we find out who's operating the Time Corridor.
得，Tegen你的问题是，你没有想象力
Come on. The trouble with you, Tegen, is that you have no imagination.
这只是一堆破砖头fixme
Just because I can’t get worked up about a load of crumbling brickwork!
- 别进来 战士们  - 什么
- Don't come in here. Soldiers!  - What?
- 他会没事的  - 你看他着装的风格
- He'll be all right.  - Look at the way he's dressed
他一定是从时间走廊下来的
He must have come down the Time Corridor.
-  你必须帮我   - 发生了什么事
- You've got to help me. - What happened?
时间走廊在下一层 小心点儿
The Time Corridor's on the next level. Be careful.
很黑...是不是?
Dark...isn't it?
- 小心四周. - 我没看到Galloway的尸体.
- Look around. - I can't see Galloway's body.
博士 你看
Look, Doctor.
子弹
Bullets.
- 新的弹壳 - 不太可能是外星人
- Recently fired. - Hardly alien.
为什么广而告之你是谁 啊
Why advertise who you are, huh?
Turlough人呢
Where's Turlough?
Turlough?
他去哪儿了
Where's he gone?
Turlough?
- 你听到了吗  - 没有 长官
- Did you hear that? - No, sir.
我觉得我听到什么声音了
I thought I heard voices.
Turlough!
需要帮助吗 先生  这里是私人产业
May I help you, gentlemen? This is private property.
不好意思 我的一个朋友在这儿走失了 我们正在找他
I'm sorry about this, this friend of mine wandered in here by mistake and we're looking for him.
我没看到人
I haven't seen him.
- 发生什么事了  - 确切的说我也正在查
- What's going on?  - Precisely what I'm trying to find out.
- 谁在那儿  - 请不要伤害她
- Who's there?  - Don't harm her, please!
- 她是朋友  - 对不起 博士
- She's a friend.  - Sorry, Doctor.
- 看   - 那是什么
- Look!  - What is it?
是个Dalek！快躲起来
A Dalek! Take cover!
消灭 消灭 消灭!
Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
消灭 消灭
Exterminate! Exterminate!
戴立克的复兴
- 你要服役多久  - 两年
- How long is your tour of duty? - Two years.
队长通常允许新人们先住下
Captain normally allows new arrivals to settle in,
再给他们分配看守的无聊差事
before subjecting them to the tedium of Officer-of-the-Watch.
- 你是做什么的 - 我呀 抱怨
- What did you do? - I complained.
有人警告过你吗
Someone should have warned you.
我有这个权利 你有看过防御系统吗
I had every right. Have you seen the state of the defence system?
- 你怕被袭击  - 重点不是那个
- You fear attack? - That's not the point.
喔 我可不担心 在这周围我看到的唯一船只是我们的供给船
Oh, I wouldn't worry about it.The only ship we ever see around here is our supply vessel.
我想，或许你过早下结论了
I think you may have spoken too soon.
感应器在禁区发现了一条有曲速驱动的飞船
Sensors have picked up a ship in the exclusion zone.
-  通知队长 - 现在先不要烦他
- Inform the captain. - I wouldn't bother him. Not yet.
这有可能是任何东西 让战士们先检查一下
It could be anything. Let the fighters check it out first.
他们会很乐意实践的
They'll be grateful for the practice!
检查完毕 所有系统工作正常
Checklist completed, all systems functioning.
增强力场
Raise the force shield.
所有部队到战斗岗位
All troopers to battle stations.
以战争速度行进
Battle speed!
士兵领队打开了视频 是艘巡洋航战舰
Fighter leader has made visual contact. It's a battle cruiser!
升级到红色警报 快通知队长
Go to red alert. Inform the captain.
感应器发送报告显示我们正在被扫描 长官
Sensors report we're being scanned, sir.
立即开启红色警报
Red alert at once!
我们被打中了
We've been hit!
- 发生了什么事？  - 工程部报告……
- What's happening? - Engineering report...
-  怎么了  - 发电厂被破坏了
- What's happening? - Damage to the generating plant.
长官 战舰正在靠进
Cruiser's closing in, sir.
我跟战士们失联了
I've lost contact with the fighters.
开火
Open fire!
快开火
I said open fire!
我做不到
I can't!
我们没有足够的能量使用镭射炮 我们没有防御
We don't have enough power for the laser cannon. We're defenceless!
- 战舰准备停靠了 - 哪个气闸
- Cruiser preparing to dock. - Which airlock?
-3号。维护队已经在处理了
Three. Maintenance team's working on it.
我希望所有人都下去那里
I want every available man down there.
用能找到的所有东西堵住走廊
Block the corridor with anything they can find.
- 他们停稳还要多久  - 3分钟
- How long before they dock? - Three minutes.
- 我们最好去气闸那里 - 好吧
- We'd better go down to the airlock. - Right.
一旦他们登舰 立刻毁掉犯人
Should we be boarded, destroy the prisoner.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-  被袭击了 快撤退   - 快撤退 被袭击了
- Under attack! Withdraw! - Withdraw! Under attack!
- 重建伍队 重建队伍
- Regroup! Regroup!
傻瓜 我告诉你们过会有这情况，他们会在走廊里布雷的
Fools! I told you this would happen, they'd mine the corridor!
必须继续进攻!
The attack must continue!
这次要按我的计划来
Only this time as I planned.
开火
Fire!
戴上面具 戴上面具
Masks down! Masks down!
移走它
Move it!
我们完了 每个人都保护好自己
We're finished. It's every man for himself!
毁灭犯人
Destroy the prisoner.
没用
It's not working!
噢 就没一个东西能正常工作吗
Oh! Does nothing work properly?
试试这里
Try here!
什么味道
What's that smell?
好了 炸药待发
Right, explosive charges primed.
那是什么味儿
What is that smell?
- 向后退 - 救救我
- Keep back. - Help me!
离我远点儿
Stay away!
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
不
No!
解除武装
Disarmed.
放了Davros
Release Davros.
- 有静电干扰 无法接通总部 - 时间走廊的副作用
- It's static. I can't get through to HQ. - Side effect of the Time Corridor.
安静
Be quiet!
如果他们还在那儿等着...怎么办
What if they're still in there...waiting?
我们必须警告自己人
We must warn our own people.
-  用时间走廊  - 你是个战士 你的忠诚呢
- Use the Time Corridor? - You're a soldier, where's your loyalty?
我只是个军需官  没有被培训上战场
I'm a quartermaster sergeant, I'm not combat-trained.
真受不了你的原则
I can't afford your principles.
看看我 状态很糟 甚至都跑不动
Look at me, I'm not in condition, I can't even run properly.
我同情你
You're pathetic!
- 我们投降吧  - 不
- We should surrender! - No!
那还差不多
That too.
- 没有防护盾 我们就无法抵抗 -  屠杀会持续多久
- We can't fight without a deflector shield! - How long will this slaughter continue?
- 博士 我们正困在时间里 - 我知道
- Doctor, we're weaving in time. - Yes, I know.
- 我们不能实体化吗  - 等我们走出时间走廊的时候就可以
- Can't we materialise? - When we're free of the Time Corridor.
- 队长人呢  - 死了
- Where's the captain? - Dead.
- 真的吗  - 如果我什么都做不了就不行
- Is that true? - Not if I have anything to do with it!
噢 不
Oh, no!
你的愤怒会更容易把我们引导给敌人 医生
Your bile would be better directed against the enemy!
- 他们消失了 - 他们应该已经关闭了时间走廊
- They've gone. - They could've closed the Time Corridor.
-  我们出去吧 - 走廊的入口在这儿
- Let's get out. - The Corridor entrance is here.
现在这儿什么都没有
There's nothing there now!
那是什么
What was that?
一种啮齿动物
A rodent.
- 查下维护队还要多久 - 好的
- Check how long the maintenance crew'll be.- All right.
穿着战靴
Wearing combat boots?
回去楼梯上 快
Back to the stairs, quick!
-  舰艇靠岸了 -  舰艇靠岸了
- The cruiser's docked. - The cruiser's docked!
- 放下防护盾  - 快点 往下拉
- Get the shield down! - Come on, pull!
- 你能看到什么吗  - 快从这里出去
- Can you see anything? - Get out of here!
往下拉
Pull!
Galloway?
我要休息下 饿死了 上一顿还是昨天吃的
I must rest. I'm hungry. I haven't eaten since yesterday.
Galloway!
- 谁在控制着时间走廊  - 不知道 你有东西给我吃吗
- Who's controlling the Time Corridor? - I don't know. Have you anything to eat?
噢, Galloway.
Oh, Galloway.
- 你打哪儿来  - 地球
- Where are you from? - Earth.
但是不是所有的犯人都来自于同一时期
But not all prisoners are from the same period.
我们在等什么
What are we waiting for?
- 你真的没东西吃吗  - 放松  我现在要进仓库
- You sure you've nothing to eat? - Relax. I'm going into the warehouse.
我在等合适的时机冲出时间走廊
A right moment.I'm waiting for the right moment to break out of the Time Corridor.
不 我跟你说过了那里有士兵
No! I told you, there are soldiers.
- 我能回我房间吗 我觉得不舒服 - 太晚了 Tegan,抓紧
- Can I get to my room? I feel sick. - Too late, Tegan, hold on.
呃 也许他们可以告诉我们发生了什么事呢
Perhaps they can tell us what's going on, huh?
抓紧
Hold on!
iCelery军团倾情奉献
神秘博士
第21季 第4集
iCelery军团倾情奉献
神秘博士
第21季 第4集
校对：NO MORE
翻译：nancydodo
第一部分
本字幕根据知识共享-署名-相同方式共享-4.0国际（CC-BY-SA4.0)协议发布
http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/deed.zh
翻译：nancydodo 校对：NO MORE
后期：小鱼干 监制：于昊源
iCelery
军团
-  哪条路  - 有关系吗
- Which way? - Does it matter?
你的策略没用 他们的位置很有利
Your tactics won't work, their position's too strong.
你们继续 我们应该试试你的计划!
You may proceed! We shall try your plan!
我们在哪儿
Where are we?
但是如果失败了, 你就要被处决了!
But should you fail, you will be exterminated!
- 他们去哪儿了  - 还能去哪 快
- Where've they gone? - Where do you think? Come on!
那是个废墟 他们不该走出仓库的
That was a shambles! They should never have got out of the warehouse!
- 谁下令使用全自动手枪得  - 上头 这对地球来说是时代错误
- Who ordered use of machine pistols? - Orders. Nothing anachronistic to Earth.
我们是在屠杀稀有种族 下次用激光枪代替
So we slaughter valuable specimens! Next time use stun lasers.
- 真是不幸的错误 - 让它成为最后一个 不然你就要被处决了
- An unfortunate mistake. - Make it your last or you'll be executed.
开启防护盾  封闭气闸
Operate the deflector shield. Seal airlocks.
- 你没事吧  - 我没办法把大家弄出时间走廊
- All right? - I can't free us from the Time Corridor!
士兵们被袭击了
The cruiser's attacked the fighters.
- 我们要去支援他们吗  - 不要
- Can we give them supporting fire? - No.
- 就不能做点什么吗  - 震荡得太厉害了
- Is there anything you can do? - Too much turbulence.
- 除了3号气闸 其它的都关闭了 - 红色警报
- All but airlock three is sealed. - Alert maintenance.
等一下就会稳定了
Things must stabilise soon.
跟我来
Come with me!
Turlough!
不可能是犯人吧
It can't be the prisoner.
时间走廊 外星人事件  真的吗
Time Corridors, alien beings! Really!
你可能不相信我们 但是时间走廊入口在这层...
You may not believe us, but the entrance to the Time Corridor is on this level...
…的某个地方
..somewhere.
有意思  你看起来并不相信我们 是吗
Interesting! You don't disbelieve us, do you?
是嘛  我从来没听过这样的事
Of course, I've never heard such nonsense!
- 你发现了什么  - 什么都没有 把他们带走
- What have you discovered? - Nothing. Take them away.
告诉他们 上校 他们已经猜得八九不离十了
Tell them, Colonel, they've guessed most of it.
- 你们是报社的人吗  - 你发现了什么 告诉我
- Are you from the Press? - What have you found? Tell me!
外星人
Alien objects?
- 通知总部这边发生的一切 - 是 长官
- Inform HQ about what's happened. - OK, sir.
- 桥已经被占领了 长官 - 很好 我们必须加入他们
- The bridge has been secured, sir. - Good, we must join them.
侦测到博士在仓库里.
The Doctor has been detained in the warehouse.
派一个Dalek去. 立刻把他带到船上来!
Despatch a Dalek. He must be brought to our ship at once!
遵命!
I obey!
- 我受不了啦 - 抓紧
- I can't stand much more. - Hold on!
我们出来了
We're free.
- 结束了吗  - 暂时是的
- Is it over? - For the moment.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
应该没事
Yes, I think so.
这个站点在这里多久了
How long has the station been in this state?
- 自从常规检查停止后 - 现在都变得七零八落了
- Since regular inspections ceased. - It's falling to pieces.
你看到的还算好的
You're seeing it on a good day.
如果你想看到一切都是崭新的 那你不该在监狱工作 卧槽
If you want everything spick and span, you shouldn't work at a prison. Come on!
你是怎么处理这些乱七八糟的事情的
How do you cope with that mess?
装作看不见
By ignoring it.
我只关心工作人员和囚犯的医疗条件
My only concern is the medical welfare of the crew and the prisoners.
难道那不是责任感的体现吗
Isn't that a narrow view of your responsibilities?
住口 这是保持理智的唯一方法
Shut up! It's the only way to stay sane.
你在这儿才三天 你什么都不知道
You've only been here three days.
等我指令
Wait until I give the order.
我在这儿够久了 久到都知道了这儿的士气低落到多吓人
I've been here long enough to learn that the morale here is appalling.
- 如果头头儿都不关心 我何苦管它呢  - 到底为什么
- If the captain doesn't care, why must I? - Why, indeed?
我的任务八周后就完成了
My tour of duty finishes in eight weeks.
我需要为下次升职准备个好报告
I need a good report for my next promotion.
- 我明白了 - 我可不这样想
- I see. - I don't think you do.
不然我还要在这儿待两年
Or I could be here for another two years!
开火
Fire!
如果主管们知道了这儿的士气 队长就等着下岗吧
If control were aware of the morale, the captain wouldn't be in command.
以前也不是没试过 通常是像你这样没经验的新人
It's been tried before, usually by inexperienced new boys like you.
博士 我们正跟时间走廊相平行呢
Doctor, we're travelling parallel to the Time Corridor.
现在 就是现在
Now. Now!
-  我们正在往哪儿去  -  看起来像是20世纪的地球
- Where are we going? - 20th-century Earth, it seems.
- 他们多久会再打过来  - 不久
- How long before they try again? - Soon.
-  我们不能先发制人吗  - 不能
- Can't we take the fight to them? - I think not!